注：Secret Informant意思是秘密线人，但是内容都是美食
rice is everywhere in Asia and there
在亚洲米饭是主食
制作米饭的方式各不相同
注：中文字幕是官方字幕，未经过修改，而英文字幕和中文字幕的时间轴没对齐，
好像还只是自动英文字幕……看看中文就好了
seems to be a near infinite amount of
ways to prepare it in Hong Kong one of
在香港 有一种历史悠久而且能把饭做的非常好吃的做法
the oldest and tastiest ways is to cook
就是把饭放在沙锅里用高温煮
注：旁白是techlinked的Riley，本视频上传于20180817
it in a clay pot over extreme heat the
碰到砂锅的这一层饭在煮好后会变成香脆可口的锅巴
rice at the edges of the pod end up
getting nice and crispy when you mix it
锅巴和沙锅里的其它菜一起吃的时候
in with the rest of the dish it adds a
脆脆的焦焦的口感很香很好味
satisfying crunch and smoky flavor the
煲仔饭也有很多不同的种类
number of varieties of clay pot rice is
also pretty high but a common favourite
在香港坚尼地城车站附近的这家尝喜煲仔小菜餐厅里
at least at chunghae restaurant in
kennedy town is white eel and pork ribs
最广受食客喜爱的是白鳝排骨饭
little off the beaten path for Hong Kong
和其他一些较为人知的港式餐厅不同
tourists chunghae actually specializes
尝喜餐厅的港式点心和煲仔饭都是他们的特色菜
in both dim sum and claypot rice but
在我们开始吃东西之前
before we dig in Olivia
先有请我们香港站的荣誉 Tattler - Olivia
one of our Hong Kong toddlers and
curator of HK food snob on Instagram get some background on the food
采访一下尝喜的老板 Jacky 获得一些内幕消息
这家尝喜煲仔小菜餐厅已经有十多年了
一开始我们开这家餐厅的初衷呢
同时也是我们餐厅的招牌特色
就是和大家分享我们的煲仔饭
煲仔饭在过去的数十年里
在中国受到广泛地接受以及喜爱
米饭结合不同的食材放在砂锅里面煮熟
食材的香与味能够很好地锁在砂锅里
客人可以品尝到新鲜
我个人最喜欢的一道菜呢是
白鳝排骨饭
我们会用上好的白鳝和排骨作为煲仔饭的食材
用上好的新鲜食材烹制出人间美味
厨房师傅对做菜的热情
以及我们所用的食材的等级
是我们尝喜餐厅开店十多年来成功的秘诀
多谢你
不客气
[Music]
这些是什么呀
we are looking at three dishes this is
在我们面前有三道菜
the most like famous dish the clique
这道是这里最最有名的招牌菜
applies with eel and sparrows no no we
白鳗排骨煲仔饭
我们一般在开吃之前会在饭上淋一些酱油増味
drizzle soy sauce on top
这一大块就是白鳗哦
对啊 没错哦
I assume that was a very good I got a
这块肉厚得让我以为这是鱼肉
我不知道鳗鱼是鱼类
我嚼到一块骨头
好好吃哦
有骨头
bone where do you I got a bone to pick
我要找你茬了 老兄
with you buddy Joyce those little
这煲仔饭尝起来有股好闻的烟熏味
我吃到的这块饭很脆 很好味
淋上去的酱油能吊一些鲜味
friends along as well and all of us
他们会在饭里放很多青葱
dahlias yeah
黑豆等一些増味料
我可以尝的出来青葱给饭带来一股清香味
aliens so this is try flowers stir-fried
这道菜是韭菜花炒银鱼干
with dried whitebait
这是中国韭菜哦 Riley
so the main part of this is the chives
这道菜的主要成分是韭菜
themselves hmmm that's surprisingly like
尝起来的口感出人意料的新鲜
fresh
that makes sense mommy there's umami in
鲜味吼
绝对鲜美
there you have the onion kinda like hits
第一口咬下去青葱的味道很强烈
you right away it's like ah you know
我觉得这些菜搭配起来吃很完美
this is like the perfect thing they need
which be like in between just because
互相之间就好像是
it's lingo it's like when you're eating
就像是你吃寿司的时候搭配生姜
sushi and you have that piece of ginger
how did Spencer yeah as a palate
有起到清除口中杂味的作用
cleanser it's almost like a salad it's
这不就是一道沙拉么
是诶
就像是沙拉拌了一些脆脆的东西在里面
like a salad recipe minutes yeah it's
not it's not a salad but like it's a
脆脆的不过又不是很脆
Frenchie but it's not too crunchy also
这里面也有一些辣辣的辣椒
there's a little bit of heat in there
like peppers yeah this is a black
有些小辣
这道菜叫黑醋一字骨
vinegar experience this sauce any family
当我看到如此乌漆嘛黑的酱料就会很激动
sauce is that dark I get excited that's
我们开吃吧
dig in
yeah that's thing it's a barn nice
天哪 这好大一块哦
黏黏的
that's a big that's too big it's very
这一块太大了啦
我的天哪
这酱汁好黏哦
sticky No
不好 我夹不起来
Oh Oh
goose our that they used to back there
不是太酸吼
他们用黑醋做这道菜可能会觉得吃起来会很酸
but I already power but perfect
调味很完美
gentleman I was gonna say is that a lot
我正好想说
很多时候看到这样黑色酱汁
of time with a black sauce like this you
都会马上以为它很甜很腻
kind of expect it to be just like really
sweet and rich yeah but this kind of
不过这道酱汁因为加了醋所以口味很特别
like has a bit of a kick to it because
of the vinegar there's not really like a
这排骨并没有让人讨厌的味道
card like you can taste it but I thought
表面厚厚的一层酱汁
it just because when you see like a big
saucer fight there's gonna be like this
我原本以为它的味道会很强烈让人难以接受
strong heart constantly noxious yeah
这味道并不让人讨厌
是啊
like you
像你自己么
没错哦
well thank you so much Olivia for taking
非常感谢 Olivia 带我们来品尝了这道地的香港煲仔饭
this to this particular place yeah yeah
我们早上只吃了一点点心
晚上吃到了这么丰盛的一桌料理
这些菜都很用心
and this is Artie that's a good word to
用心这个词用在这里很准确
describe it Wow Messier rips its sticks
让你回味无穷
to your abs all right on to the next
我们下一次美食大冒险
food adventure yeah later
明天
嗯 过会儿再说吧
I'm working here Alex thanks for
我在工作呢 Alex
感谢你观看我们的这一集视频
watching this video which is produced by
本集视频由 Tattle 制作播出
tattle
if you don't know tattle is a brand new
如果你还没有听说
Tattle 是一个帮助冒险者找到当地向导的一个平台
platform connecting savvy locals with
curious explorers check us out on social
订阅我们的频道以及每周电子期刊
media and sign up for our newsletter at
可以在视频下面的简介里找到相关链接
the link in the description
big thanks to shin-hey for having us and
大力感谢尝喜餐厅对我们的热情款待
thanks to Olivia for being our Tattler
也感谢 Olivia 作为我们这一集的 Tattler
for this episode
check out her Instagram in the
快点击下面的链接看看 Olivia 的IG频道吧
description below as well